arounder.com 2016-12-16

# Privacy Policy | Monster Supplements

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Our Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the highest-quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our clients and partners. The Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services. This statement will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers' needs.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

When you visit our Web site you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

**1\. Personal Information You Choose to Provide**

Personal Information

If you choose to request further information on our products or services from us or our partners, you may need to give personal information and authorization to obtain this information. For example, you may need to provide the following information:

Name   
Mailing address   
Email address   
Home and business phone number   
Other personal information (e.g. mother's maiden name)   
Email Information

In addition to providing the foregoing information to our partners, if you choose to correspond further with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.

**2\. Web Site Use Information**

Similar to commercial Web sites, our Web site utilizes a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, What Are Cookies?) and Web server logs to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual.

**How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing customer service and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our traditional corporate standards designed to safeguard the security and privacy of our customers' personal information. As a customer, you will be given the opportunity, at least once annually, to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers.

**What Are Cookies?**

Cookies are a feature of Web browser software that allows Web servers to recognize the computer used to access a Web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's Web browser on the user's hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one Web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that Web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related Web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from Web page to Web page and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.

**How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?**

We use Web site browser software tools such as cookies and Web server logs to gather information about our Web site users' browsing activities, in order to constantly improve our Web site and better serve our customers. This information assists us to design and arrange our Web pages in the most user-friendly manner and to continually improve our Web site to better meet the needs of our customers and prospective customers.

Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by users to our Web site as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our Web site and evaluate our Web site's visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information about you although they do permit us to send focused online banner advertisements or other such responses to you.

**Notice of New Services and Changes**

Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Web site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. As our client, you will be given the opportunity to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers by clicking on a response box when you receive such an offer or by sending us an email request at info@monstersupplements.com.

**Evaluation of Information Protection Practices**

Periodically, our operations and business practices are reviewed for compliance with corporate policies and procedures governing the security, confidentiality and quality of our information.

**Employee Access, Training and Expectations**

Our corporate values, ethical standards, policies and practices are committed to the protection of customer information. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information, and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes and transactions.

**Do We Disclose Information to Outside Parties?**

We may provide aggregate information about our customers, sales, Web site traffic patterns and related Web site information to our affiliates or reputable third parties, but this information will not include personally identifying data, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy.

**What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?**

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights.

**What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Web site.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Web site to another Web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including Web sites which have a link on our Web site, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**Your Consent**

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

**Visitors to our website**

When someone visits [www.monstersupplements.com](http://monstersupplements.com/) we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

**Use of cookies by Monster Supplements**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

**Cookie**

| 

**Name**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**More information**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Digital Window

| 

_aw_m_3596  
awin

| 

Affiliate Window cookies track the activity of affiliates and reward them for generating traffic and sales on our websites. 

| 

Go to [Affiliate Window](http://www.affiliatewindow.com/documents/Privacy%20Policy.pdf "Affiliate window") for more information on managing Affiliate Window cookies.  
  
Monster Supplements Session ID

| 

PHPSESSID

| 

A session cookie is required to follow your progress through the website. It is essential to ensure that any information you enter or routes you take are remembered by the website. Without this cookie, every page you visited would treat you as a completely new visitor. This cookie does not identify you personally and is not linked to any other information we store about you. The cookie is deleted when you close your web browser.

|   
  
HelloBar

| 

hellobar_current  
hellobar_1331835052_visited  
hellobar_1331835052_shown  
hellobar_1331835052_variation

| 

HelloBar cookies track click activity on the drop down promotional bar. This cookie does not contain any personal data.

| 

Go to [HelloBar](http://www.hellobar.com/privacy-policy "Criteo") for more information on managing HelloBar cookies.  
  
Monster Supplements Email Tracking Cookie

| 

emailTrackingCookie

| 

When we send emails to our own registered Monster Supplements customers, we’ll sometimes track who opened the emails and who went so far as to click on any of the hyperlinks. We do this to measure the performance of our Email Campaigns, and to improve our offerings to specific customer segments.

|   
  
Criteo

| 

extid  
acdc  
uid  
uic  
evt  
udc  
udi< br /> dis  
OACBLOCK  
OACCAP

| 

Criteo provides you with personalised adverts when you visit selected other websites by placing a Criteo cookie on your computer. This cookie does not contain any personal data. 

| 

Go to [Criteo](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy "Criteo") for more information on managing Criteo cookies.  
  
Twitter

| 

guest_id

| 

guest_id is a guest or Twitter account identifier.

| 

Go to [Twitter](http://twitter.com/privacy) for more information on managing Twitter cookies.  
  
Facebook

| 

locale  
datr  
lu  
csm

| 

Facebook cookies enables you to interact with our website using your Facebook account.

| 

Go to [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) for more information on managing Facebook cookies.  
  
Bing

|  | 

Bing cookies originate in our PPC campaigns with Bing, rewarding them for generating traffic and sales on our website 

| 

Go to [Bing](http://bingppc.com/privacy "Bing") for more information on managing Bing cookies.  
  
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**YouTube cookies**

We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube's embedding videos information page](http://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780 "External link").
